vitaminsAndMineralsQuestions = [
    {
        "question": "Which individuals require vitamin supplementation",
		"choices": "specific deficiencies, medical indications, conditions affecting absorption, conditions affecting vitamin need, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "General recommendations for multivitamins that is false is",
		"choices": "look for 100%, thiamine, riboflavin, niacin, B6, folic acid, B12, D, E, and C, limit vitamin C and minerals other than calcium and magnesium, include vitamin K unless there is anticoagulant use",
        "answer": "limit vitamin C and minerals other than calcium and magnesium",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "How is vitamin intake quantitated",
		"choices": "dietary reference intakes, recommended dietary allowance, daily value, tolerable upper intake level, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Select all the active forms of vitamin A",
		"choices": "retinol, retinal, beta carotene, retinoic acid",
        "answer": "retinol, retinal",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a normal function of vitamin A",
        "choices": "Rhodopsin, epithelial barrier, antioxidant, cell replication, cell division and transcription",
		"answer": "cell division and transcription",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Where do you look for vitamin deficiency in vitamin A: p____, s____, f____ oil, i____ fat absorption",
		"answer": "pregnancy, smoking, fish oil, impaired",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the signs of vitamin A deficiency, dry, s____ skin, increased infectious diseases such as m____, m____, d____ eyes, impaired a____, t____, s____",
		"answer": "scaly, measles, malaria, dry, appetite, taste, smell",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin A excess leads to",
		"choices": "increased lung cancer risk in smokers, bleeding, liver toxicity, joint and bone pain, risk of osteoporosis, dry skin, gingivitis, birth defects, alopecia, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The three different forms of vitamin D are e____, c____, 1,25-d____",
		"answer": "ergocalciferol, cholecalciferol, dihydroxycholecalciferol",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Ergocalciferol (D2) is present in p____ and f____",
        "answer": "plants, fungi",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "cholecalciferol (D3) is synthesized in skin in presence of s____, present in f____ foods",
        "answer": "sunlight, fortified",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcitriol (Rocaltrol) is a p____ product",
        "answer": "prescription",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin D excess leads to ____ complaints, h____",
        "answer": "GI, hypercalcemia",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal function of vitamin E",
		"choices": "antioxidant protection against damage, involvement in immune function, inhibition of protein kinase C, decreases endothelial adhesion, increases vasodilation, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the daily requirement of vitamin D for male/female (1-70yo) ____ug/day ( ____IU)",
        "answer": "15, 600",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the daily requirement of vitamin D for male/female (70+ yo) ____ug/day (____IU)",
        "answer": "20, 800",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the UL for vitamin D (>=9yo) ____ug/day (____IU)",
        "answer": "100, 4000",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "You need to watch Vit D in e____, lack of s____, lack of m____, l____/kidney damage",
        "answer": "elderly, sun, milk, liver",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin E deficiency leads to free radical damage to neuronal, muscle, and other membranes, p____ neuropathy, r____, a____, impaired immune function",
        "answer": "peripheral, retinopathy, ataxia",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin E excess leads to increased bleeding at high doses, i____ mortality, decreased effect of r____ therapy",
        "answer": "increased, radiation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a normal function of thiamine",
		"choices": "carbohydrate metabolism, nervous function, gain fat",
        "answer": "gain fat",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Dry beriberi affects p____ nervous system",
        "answer": "peripheral",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wet beriberi affects c____ system",
        "answer": "cardiovascular",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Wernicke's encephalopathy is the acute phase and includes c____, a____, e____ weakness/p____",
        "answer": "confusion, ataxia, eye, paralysis",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Korsakoff's syndrome is the chronic phase and includes memory loss and visual impairment and is known as a____induced persisting a____disorder and can be irreversible",
        "answer": "alcohol, amnestic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What is the normal function of riboflavin",
		"choices": "Electron transport and ATP production, Glutathione reductase (antioxidant), flavoproteins, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Riboflavin deficiency needs to be watched in e____, a____, some drugs",
        "answer": "elderly, alcoholics",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Riboflavin deficiency is also known as a____",
        "answer": "ariboflavinosis",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "riboflavin deficiency results in",
		"choices": "scaly skin, sore mouth, GI irritatiion, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "____ mg tryptophan = 1 mg niacin",
        "answer": "60",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "riboflavin has no known UL",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Which one is not a normal function of niacin",
		"choices": "NADH, NADPH, lipoprotein regulation at high doses, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "none of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niacin deficiency needs to be watched in a____, diets rich in corn not a____ with lime, i____ therapy",
        "answer": "alcoholics, alkalinized, isoniazid",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niacin deficiency leads to p____, der____, dia____, dem____",
		"answer": "pellagra, dermatitis, diarrhea, dementia",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Niacin excess leads to f____, h____ effects, h____, hyp____",
        "answer": "flushing, heart, hepatotoxicity, hyperglycemia", 
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pyridoxine is used for",
		"choices": "transamination, pyridoxyl phosphate, pyridoxamine phosphate, heme/fatty acids/neurotransmitter synthesis, energy production with folate and B12, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pyridoxine deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "peripheral neuropathy, convulsions, decreased cognition, depression, cheilosis, decreased immune function, microcytic anemia, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Pyridoxine excess leads to s____ n____",
		"answer": "sensory neuropathy",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The normal function of biotin is",
		"choices": "gluconeogenesis, fatty acid, amino acid synthesis, protein expression, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Biotin deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "thinning hair/facial rash/dermatitis, hypercholesterolemia, hyperglycemia, depression, peripheral neuropathy, GI symptoms, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Biotin deficiency needs to be watched in s____, anti____intake of r____ egg, p____",
        "answer": "smoking, convulsant, raw, pregnancy",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Biotin is synthesized by g____ bacteria",
        "answer": "gut",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "1 ug food folate= ____DFE=____ug supplement or fortified food",
		"answer": "1,0.6",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The funcion of folate is to",
		"choices": "cofactor for methylation reactions in nucleic acid synthesis and cell division, metabolism of amino acids, interaction with vitamins B6 and B12, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folic acid deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "mouth soreness and ulceration, megaloblastic anemia, including weakness, irritability, difficulty concentrating, developmental defects, neural tube, low birthweight, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folic acid excess leads to G____, C____, masking of B____ deficiency",
        "answer": "GI, CNS, 12",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Folate deficiency needs to be watched in",
		"choices": "women of child bearing age, alcoholics, smokers, some drugs, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin B12 is NOT needed for",
		"choices": "metabolism of amino acids, synthesis of DNA/hemoglobin/myeline, interacts with folate and B6, involved with homocysteine metabolism",
        "answer": "metabolism of amino acids",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin B12 deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "ataxia, confusion, depression, dementia, peripheral neuropathy, mouth soreness, pernicious anemia, impaired fetal and infant growth, increased homocysteine, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "B12 deficiency needs to be watched in v____, GI ____, GI ____",
		"answer": "vegan diet, damage, drugs",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "There is no B12 UL",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "The normal function of vitamin C is a____ activity, c____ synthesis, i____ function",
		"answer": "antioxidant, collagen, immune ",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin C deficiency leads to",
		"choices": "bruising, fatigue, depression, irritability, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin C excess leads to k____ stones, GI s____",
        "answer": "kidney, symptoms",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Vitamin C is destroyed by cooking and storage",
		"choices": "true, false",
        "answer": "true",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "General concerns regarding minerals is factors increasing absorption such as i____stomach acid, mineral d____, g____abnormalities",
        "answer": "increased, deficiency, genetic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "General concerns regarding minerals is factors decreasing absorption such as d____stomach acid, i____damage, s____ of transport proteins",
        "answer": "decreased, intestinal, saturation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "general issues regarding minerals is non absorption such as s____ texture, GI u____, d____drug absorption",
        "answer": "stool, upset, decreased",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcium deficiency leads to o____, m____ cramps, cardiac a____",
		"answer": "osteoporosis, muscle, arrhythmias",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Calcium excess leads to k____ stones, c____ precipitation, c____",
        "answer": "kidney, calcium, constipation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of calcium is ____mg/day for 9-19 yo",
        "answer": "1300",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of calcium for male/female is ____mg/day for 19-50 yo",
		"answer": "1000",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The daily requirement of calcium is ____mg/day for 51+ yo",
        "answer": "1200",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "The UL for calcium for male/female is ____/____/____mg/day for 9-19, 19-50, 51+",
		"answer": "3000, 2500, 2000",
        "type": "text"
	    },
    {
        "question": "Calcium deficiency needs to be watched in bad diets, s____, i____ with unsupplemented formula",
        "answer": "smokers, infants",
        "type": "text"	
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron deficiency leads to a____",
        "answer": "anemia",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron deficiency needs to be watched in",
		"choices": "inadequate dietary intake, decreased vitamin C, periods of rapid growth or pregnancy, normal/drug induced or pathological blood loss incuding menstruation, all of the above, none of the above",
		"answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron excess leads to GI/l____ damage from f____ radicals, c____",
        "answer": "liver, free, constipation",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "What are the different forms of iron supplements: ferrous f____, s____, g____",
		"answer": "fumarate, sulfate, gluconate",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "R____ iron is absorbed more readily than o____ iron",
        "answer": "reduced, oxidized",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "H____ iron is absorbed more readily than i____ iron",
		"answer": "heme, inorganic",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Plant sources of iron come from l____, fortified grain products, m____, s____",
        "answer": "legumes, molasses, spinach",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Iron needs to be watched in b____ loss, p____/rapid growth, p____ diet",
		"answer": "blood, pregnancy, poor",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnesium is needed for c____ for energy production, i____ transport in muscles",
		"answer": "cofactor, ion",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnesium deficiency causes",
		"choices": "irritability, poor memory, seizures, cardiac arrhythmias, fatigue, cramps, all of the above, none of the above",
        "answer": "all of the above",
        "type": "multiple"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnesium excess leads to  d____, m____ weakness",
		"answer": "diarrhea, muscle",
        "type": "text"
    },
    {
        "question": "Magnesium deficiency needs to be watched in  a____, d____ use",
        "answer": "alcoholics, diuretic",
        "type": "text"
    }
]